iihf.com 2019-04-06

# IIHF - Privacy Policy

### INTERNATIONAL ICE HOCKEY FEDERATION PRIVACY POLICY

The International Ice Hockey Federation (hereinafter referred to as “IIHF”) takes your privacy seriously. Please read the following Privacy Policy carefully to learn more about our use of Your personal identifying information that we collect when You access, use or register with the IIHF Digital Services. The IIHF is committed to undertaking reasonable measure to protect the privacy and security of all the personal information that is provided to us. The IIHF reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time without notice to You. You are, therefore, responsible for regularly reviewing this Privacy Policy. Your continued use of the Digital Services after the entry into force of this revised Privacy Policy constitutes Your confirmation of Your reading and understanding of such changes. 

### What does this Privacy Policy Cover?

This Privacy Policy applies to all IIHF digital services such as websites, newsletters, registration systems and online business resources (including but not limited to the IIHF extranet and intranet) offered on the www.iihf.com website or any other digital property created and operated by the IIHF (collectively referred to as “Digital Services”). The Privacy Policy covers the treatment of personally identifiable information that is collected when You are on, use or register for the IIHF Digital Services, as described in the IIHF Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies or entities that the IIHF does not own or control, or to people that the IIHF does not employ or manage, including without limitation, third-party advertisers or sponsors to whom You provide information. The IIHF makes its content available on a variety of third party platforms like Facebook, Twitter or YouTube and these platforms are governed by their own terms and conditions and privacy policies that we strongly recommend You read. 

### How do we collect information from You?

The IIHF collects information when You access, use and/or register on the IIHF Digital Services, when You enter into transactions, promotions, or sweepstakes that are sponsored and/or offered by the IIHF directly or via IIHF Partners from time to time, and when You register for the IIHF Ice Times or similar. The IIHF may also collect certain information when you visit our Digital Services (as a non-registered user), through cookies, pixels and similar technologies.

### What type of information is collected from You?

You may provide us with information, including personally identifiable information, when you register on the Services, create a user account, communicate with us, complete certain transactions or subscribe to Digital Services such as event registration, professional online resources or media alerts.

The personal information we collect might include, but is not limited: address, email address, last name, first name, country of residence, date of birth, gender, screen name, IP address, login information, password, information regarding what pages accessed and when, and opt-in for game,  
IIHF content preferences and promotional communications when lawful. To access certain  
business resources, the IIHF may ask you to provide additional information such as your business  
organization, job title, physical address, phone number and nationality.

The information requested will allow the IIHF to create and maintain Your user account and identify  
you as one of our users.

**Automatic Information:** When You visit the IIHF website or certain IIHF digital properties, the IIHF  
will use “cookies” to collect information. Cookies are small data files, which are transferred to a  
computer’s hard disk to memorize information like registration IDs and passwords. A cookie will  
typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has originated, the “lifetime” of the  
cookie and various values.

The IIHF uses “first party cookies – ID cookies” to enable certain features on the IIHF website or  
certain IIHF digital properties, to better understand how You interact with the IIHF website and  
digital properties and to monitor aggregate usage by IIHF website and IIHF digital properties’  
users and web traffic routing. The IIHF uses either session cookies (duration of Your visit) or  
persistent cookies (stays on Your computer until You clear your browser).

The IIHF also uses “third party cookies” to enable certain services to us such as analytics and  
advertising. For example the IIHF uses google analytics to be able to measure traffic and  
performance of Digital Services.

You can always block cookies by updating Your web browser privacy settings. To do so, You will  
have to access the “Help” menu in Your browser’s menu bar and search for the term “cookies”. If  
You decline acceptance of cookies or block cookies, please note that You may experience less  
customized experience on this Website. 

### Why do You have to Register?

The IIHF content is generally available on the Digital Services without the need to register as a  
user. However, certain personalization options, transactions or services (such as e-commerce,  
newsletters, professional services or event registration services) offered on IIHF Digital Services  
require that you register with the IIHF and provide certain information about You. 

### How is Your Information Used?

The IIHF uses and processes Your personal information collected to: 

  * Customize the content You see on IIHF Digital Services
  * For research, development and analytical purposes
  * To fulfill Your requests for certain products and/or services
  * ​To communicate with You
  * For activities, promotions and/or campaigns of the IIHF or IIHF partners
  * To send You communication when You have opted-in to receive certain types of information from the IIHF.

The IIHF reviews its retention periods for personal information on a regular basis. The IIHF is  
legally required to hold some types of information to fulfil our statutory obligations. The IIHF will  
hold Your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant activity,  
or as long as is set out in any relevant contract You hold with us. 

### Who has access to Your personal information?

The IIHF will not sell or rent Your personal information to third parties. The IIHF will not share Your  
information with third parties for marketing purposes.

**Third Party Service Providers working on IIHF’s behalf:** the IIHF may pass Your personal  
information to our third-party service providers, agents, subcontractors and other associated  
organizations for the purposes of completing tasks and providing services to You on our behalf (for  
example to analyze IIHF Digital Platform fan usage, infrastructure and general IT services, email  
communications and push notifications, accreditation, arranging travel or accommodation, etc.).  
However, when the IIHF uses third party service providers, the IIHF discloses only the personal  
information that is necessary to deliver the service. Further, we have a contract in place that  
ensure confidentiality and requires them to keep Your information secure and not to use it for their  
own direct marketing purposes. Please be assured that we will not release Your personal  
information to third parties beyond the IIHF network for them to use for their own direct marketing  
purposes, unless you have requested us to do so, or we are required to do so by law, for example,  
by a court or for the purpose of prevention of fraud or other crimes.

**Third Party Product Providers the IIHF works in association with:** the IIHF works closely with  
various other third-party product providers (for example the IIHF Official World Championship  
Merchandizing Partner and IIHF Championships Authorized Ticket Brokers) and various IIHF  
Partners (NIKE, GRAF, etc.) which have links to their website via IIHF website or digital properties.  
When utilizing Your information, the third-party service provider and IIHF Partner will be acting as  
the data controller of Your information. The IIHF partners and third-party product provider, and not  
the IIHF, are responsible for the treatment of your personal information when the IIHF partners or  
third-party product provider utilize Your personal information. If You choose to directly register with  
an IIHF partner or third-party product provider’s websites at the same time You register with the  
IIHF Digital Services, the terms of the Privacy Policy of the IIHF partner or third-party service shall  
be incorporate herein by reference. 

### How do we Protect Your Personal Information?

**Data Security:** The IIHF has adopted reasonable security measures, appropriate to the sensitivity  
of the personal information, against unauthorized access, disclosure, loss or destruction of  
personal information. These measures may include technological, physical and organization  
methods of security. However, the Internet is an open system and we cannot guarantee that  
unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat those measures or use your personal  
information for improper purposes.

If You communicate with the IIHF by email, You should note that the secrecy of Internet email is  
uncertain. By sending sensitive or confidential email messages or information which is not  
encrypted You accept the risk of such uncertainty and possible lack of confidentiality over the  
Internet.

**International Transfer:** Your information is primarily processed in Switzerland and the European  
Union but may be stored and used elsewhere depending on the location of affiliates, partners, and  
other entities who are permitted to access such information under the terms of this Privacy Policy  
(for example a company helping us provide a Digital Service). Such other locations, like the United  
States of America, do not provide in their laws the level of protection of your privacy equivalent to  
the one applied in the European Union or Switzerland. By accessing, using or registering for the  
IIHF Digital Services or submitting personal information to the IIHF, you specifically agree to the  
transfer any related purpose.

**Children’s Privacy:** The IIHF does not knowingly collect personal information from Children. The  
IIHF does not take specific steps to protect the privacy of children who disclose their personal  
information to the IIHF. If the IIHF becomes aware that a child has provided us with person  
information without parental consent, we will take steps to delete this information and close the  
child’s account. 

### What is the IIHF’s Legal Basis for Processing Your Personal Information?

The IIHF mainly processes Your personal information to perform our obligations under the Terms  
and Conditions but in certain cases, we also rely on other justifications:

**Contractual necessity:** contractual necessity applies for all users who are of age to enter into a  
contract by accepting our Terms and Conditions and justifies the following uses of Your personal  
information: (a) providing the Digital Services and personalizing your experience of the Digital  
Services; (b) managing registration and user accounts; (c) securing and developing the Digital  
Services; (d) communicating with You in relation to the Services; (e) sharing data with our partners  
who may offer You their services; and (f) providing You services or information that you have  
requested. In these cases, you have the right to port Your data.

**Consent:** We may process certain personal information based on explicit consent, which You can  
withdraw at any time, for the following activities: (a) send you certain marketing communications directly from the IIHF or its partners. In these cases, You have the right to port your data and  
withdraw Your consent.

**Legitimate interests:** We rely on our **legitimate interests** to provide secure and efficient Digital  
Services that are consistent with out Terms and Conditions so that our visitors, partners and fans  
may receive high quality Digital Services and may enjoy content related to their interests.  
Legitimate interests constitute a basis for the following activities: (a) making available through the  
Digital Services publicly available information related to the IIHF, IIHF Competitions, ice hockey  
leagues, clubs and players, ice hockey and news stories; (b) providing Digital Services and  
personalizing your experience of the Digital Services to Your interests; (c) managing registrations;  
(d) securing and developing the Digital Services; (e) communicating with you in relation to the  
Digital Services; (f) sharing data with our partners who may offer you their services; (g) sending  
you marketing communications, including via emails, if You have opted-in or can lawfully receive  
such communications; and (h) sharing Your Personal information with third parties including law  
enforcement authorities where we suspect an unlawful activity. In these cases, You have the right  
to object to the processing of Your personal information or ask us to restrict such processing.

**Legal Basis:** We reserve the right to disclose personal information we hold about You if we are  
required to do so under applicable laws or pursuant to any judicial or administrative process, and to  
the extent necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding unlawful activities, or violation  
of our Terms and Conditions under the legal basis described in this Privacy Policy 

### How do You Access, Correct and Contact the IIHF

To withdraw Your consent, access or rectify personal information, please adjust the respective  
settings in the IIHF Digital Platform, including unsubscribing to marketing communications. Further,  
to object to the processing of Your personal information, to withdraw Your consent or to request  
access, deletion or correction of any erroneous or incomplete personal information, to exercise your  
data portability right or for any questions related to this Privacy Policy, you can contact the IIHF at  
office@iihf.com.
